Guide to the Meyer Schapiro Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Works of art, 1920s-1980s
  - Subseries VIII.3: Paintings, 1930s-1980s
    - 2930-1121 Betsy Head Park and Playground - Brownsville, Brooklyn (Box 37)
      19 3/4 x 30 Oil paint on canvas
    - 2931-1121 Untitled (Box 37)
      30 x 24 Oil paint on canvas
    - 2932-1121 [Study after Manet] (Box 51)
      30 x 25 Oil paint on canvas
    - 2933-1121 Untitled (Box 38)
      19 x 24 1/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 2934-1121 Untitled (Box 38)
      14 x 18 3/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 2935-1121 Lillian, Miriam and Meyer (On Ladder Picking Apples) (Box 38)
      Accompanied by scopecontent: several drawings for this painting are dated 12/25/34. 18 1/2 x 14 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2936-1121 View of Hillside and Mountains - Vermont (Box 38)
      CU20 12 x 19 Oil paint on paper
    - 2937-1121 Vermont Landscape with Glebe Mountain (Box 38)
      CU3 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2938-1121 Lillian (Box 38)
      CU 57; cat.32 8 1/4 x 10 5/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 2939-1121 Lillian and Miriam - Vermont (Box 38)
      9 1/2 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2940-1121 Untitled (Box 38)
      11 x 15 Watercolor on paper
    - 2941-1121 Untitled (Box 38)
      19 x 14 5/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 2942-1121 Still Life (Box 38)
      CU 78; Accompanied by scopecontent: basement corridor. 8 3/4 x 6 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 2943-1121 Lillian (Box 38)
      CU47 11 x 8 3/8 Ink on paper
    - 2944-1121 Suspended Pieces (Box 38)
      CU76 5 1/2 x 6 1/4 Gouache on paper
    - 2945-1121 L. Sleeping (Box 38)
      CU104, cat.13 8 3/8 x 11 Ink on paper
    - 2946-1121 Lillian (Box 38)
      CU20, cat.40 16 x 10 1/4 Etching
    - 2947-1121 Branch Form (Box 38)
      CU117, cat.55 8 3/8 x 12 Gouache on paper
    - 2948-1121 Concert Hall Lobby (Box 38)
      CU82, cat.3 10 1/4 x 8 1/2 Charcoal on paper
    - 2949-1121 Lillian, Elbow on Table (Box 38)
      CU99, cat.19 8 1/2 x 11 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 2950-1121 Clarice with Sliding Board (Box 38)
      CU112, cat.30 9 x 11 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2951-1121 From Sunshine to the Sunless Land: Remembering Mark Rothko (Box 38)
      CU79, cat.58 14 x 11 Crayon on paper
    - 2952-1121 Vermont Landscape with Trees at Sunset (Box 38)
      CU5, cat.34 9 x 11 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2953-1121 War and Peace (Box 38)
      CU12, cat.47 11 3/8 x 8 Etching
    - 2954-1121 Dr. Jospeh Milgram (Box 38)
      CU108, cat.35 10 x 6 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 2955-1121 Whittaker Chambers in Europe After Reading George Moore (Box 38)
      CU D81 POL, cat.6 11 x 8 3/8 Charcoal on paper
    - 2956-1121 Study After Seurat's Drwing of a Child in LA GRAND JATTE (Box 38)
      CU27, cat.53 12 3/8 x 9 1/2 Conte crayon on paper
    - 2957-1121 Figures on the Beach (Box 38)
      CU122, cat.2 9 x 12 Oil paint on paper
    - 2958-1121 Untitled (Box 38)
      Accompanied by scopecontent: drawn by Meyer Schapiro on the beach at Siesta Key, Florida. 7 x 11 Pastels on paper
    - 2959-1121 New York Harbor (Box 38)
      CU33, cat31 8 1/2 x 11 1/2 Oil paint on paper
      Accompanied by scopecontent: corridor (near dining room). 8 1/2 x 11 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2960-1121 Riverside Park, New York, Near West Eighties (Box 38)
      CU21 12 x 16 Oil paint on canvas board
    - 2961-1121 Hudson River at Riverside Drive (Box 38)
      CU19 12 x 15 3/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 2962-1121 Siesta Key (Box 38)
      14 x 15 3/4 Pastels on paper
    - 2963-1121 L. Half-Figure, Hands Behind Head (Box 38)
      CU91 11 1/2 x 9 Ink on paper
    - 2964-1121 Picnic Surrealiste (Box 38)
      Accompanied by scopecontent: drawn for Kurt Seligman. 8 1/2 x 11 Watercolor on paper
      Accompanied by one typed and one handwritten transcription of poem inscribed on painting. 8 1/2 x 11 Watercolor on paper
    - 2965-1121 L. (Box 38)
      CU88 12 x 9 1/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 2966-1121 Ernest Fishing (Box 38)
      CU47 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2967-1121 Lillian Millgram (Box 38)
      Painted by Lillian, not Meyer Schapiro. 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2968-1121 Lillian Among Rocks at Everett Vail's Property in Rawsonville (Box 38)
      Accompanied by scopecontent: 1933 sketch for oil painting on canvas dated 1933 given by Meyer Schapiro to Sophie Esterman in 1968. 10 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2969-112 Vermont Landscape, 1 (Box 38)
      6 x 10 1/8 Watercolor on paper
    - 2970-1121 Two Heads and Leaf (Box 38)
    - 2971-1121 Hudson River at West Eighties (Box 38)
      10 x 12 1/2 Watercolor on paper
    - 2972-1121 Star Lake - Belmont, Vermont (Box 38)
      CU1 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2973-1121 Vermont Landscape with Mountain (Box 38)
    - 2974-1121 Fright (Box 38)
      CU110, cat.18 11 x 8 1/2 Crayon on paper
    - 2975-1121 Lillian (Box 38)
      CU51, cat.20 11 x 8 1/2 Crayon on paper
    - 2976-1121 Self-Portrait (Box 38)
      CU46, cat.1 11 x 8 1/2 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 2977-1121 Miriam and Ernest (Box 38)
      CU54, cat.38 12 x 9 Watercolor on paper
      Accompanied by scopecontent: April 1940, Meyer's drawing, Miriam's color 12 x 9 Watercolor on paper
    - 2978-1121 Chicken House and Shed - Vermont (Box 38)
    - 2979-1121 Shed with Clothesline - Vermont (Box 38)
      12 5/8 x 9 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 2980-1121 Vermont Landscape (Box 38)
      Accompanied by scopecontent: 279 West 4th Street. 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 Watercolor on paper
    - 2981-1121 Miscellaneous oversized photocopies (Box 38)
      Nine photocopies. Various
    - 2982-1121 Untitled (Box 39)
      Inscribed on recto: to Lloyd, with love, for his long awaited return 1/26/64. 8 1/4 x 14 Colored pencil on paper
      Accompanied by approximately fifty photocopies of original. 8 1/4 x 14 Colored pencil on paper
    - 2983-1121 Vermont (Box 39)
      19 x 12 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 2984-1121 Nude (Box 39)
      18 1/2 x 8 1/2 Charcoal on cardboard
    - 2985-1121 In Martin's Class (Box 39)
      10 7/8 x 9 1/2 Charcoal on paper
    - 2986-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 1/2 x 12 3/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 2987-1121 Miriam (Box 39)
      12 x 18 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 2988-1121 West 76th Street (Box 39)
      16 1/8 x 12 7/16 Gouache on paper
    - 2989-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 x 12 Crayon on paper
    - 2990-1121 Ernst (Box 39)
      14 5/8 x 19 1/16 Oil paint on paper
    - 2991-1121 Monotype at Yaddo (Box 39)
      16 7/8 x 12 1/4 Ink on paper
    - 2992-1121 Lillian - Drawn Left Hand or Foot (Box 39)
      19 x 12 3/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 2993-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      12 1/2 x 9 1/2 Paint on paper
    - 2994-1121 Ernst (Box 39)
      18 x 12 Charcoal on paper
    - 2995-1121 Lillian - Hair Washed (Box 39)
      19 1/2 x 12 1/2 Ink on paper
    - 2996-1121 Rawsonville - Barnes and Howse [sic] From Hill (Box 39)
      11 1/16 x 14 7/16 Oil paint on paper
    - 2997-1121 Family and Dada at Winhall (Box 39)
      16 3/8 x 12 3/4 Oil paint and graphite pencil on paper
    - 2998-1121 Untitled (Box 39)
      14 1/2 x 19 Crayon on paper
    - 2999-1121 Untitled (Box 39)
    - 3000-1121 Miriam (Box 39)
    - 3001-1121 Hyde Salomon at Yaddo (Box 39)
      117 x 13 3/4 Crayon on paper
    - 3002-1121 Lillian in Mexican Blouse (Box 39)
      12 3/4 x 19 1/8 Charcoal on paper
    - 3003-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      12 1/2 x 18 3/4 Gouache on paper
    - 3004-1121 Sketches After Painting (Box 39)
      18 x 12 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 3005-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      15 1/8 x 12 1/8 Gouache on paper
    - 3006-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19x 12 Crayon on paper
    - 3007-1121 Rawsonville - Barnes [sic] and Houses (Box 39)
      14 7/8 x 11 1/16 Oil paint on paper
    - 3008-1121 Lillian Nursing Ernst (Box 39)
      18 x 12 Crayon on paper
    - 3009-1121 Vermont (Box 39)
    - 3010-1121 Lillian and Miriam (Box 39)
    - 3011-1121 A Concert in Carnigy [sic] Hall (Box 39)
      14 x 17 6/8 Charcoal on paper
    - 3012-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 7/8 x 13 7/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 3013-1121 Miriam (Box 39)
    - 3014-1121 Untitled (Box 39)
      16 3/4 x 23 Paint on paper
    - 3015-1121 Vermont Hill House (Box 39)
      12 x 16 3/4 Gouache on paper
    - 3016-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 1/8 x 12 Charcoal on paper
    - 3017-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 x 14 3/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 3018-1121 Woman in Bathing Suit (Box 39)
      19 x 12 1/8 Charcoal on paper
    - 3019-1121 Miriam (Box 39)
    - 3020-1121 Young Man (Box 39)
      19 x 12 `1/8 Crayon on paper
    - 3021-1121 Miriam, Ernst (Box 39)
      19 7/8 x 13 7/8 Crayon on paper
    - 3022-1121 Lillian Asleep in Folding Chair (Box 39)
      12 1/2 x 19 Charcoal on paper
    - 3023-112 Lillian, 1 (Box 39)
      12 3/4 x 19 Charcoal on paper
    - 3024-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 x 12 3/4 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 3025-1121 [Shoe-Shine in Union Square] (Box 39)
      12 7/16 x 19 Gouache on paper
    - 3026-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 1/16 x 14 5/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 3027-1121 Lillian - Brownsville (Box 39)
      19 x 12 3/4 Charcoal on paper
    - 3028-1121 Lillian (Box 39)
      19 1/8 x 12 7/8 Charcoal on paper
    - 3029-1121 Chinese Head (Box 39)
      See item 3035 for additional print and item 3049 for corresponding plate. 25 x 15 1/4 Ink on paper
    - 3030-1121 Barnes and Howse [sic] with Line Holder - Rawsonville (Box 39)
      11 1/16 x 14 15/16 Oil paint on paper
    - 3031-1121 Family in Vermont (Box 39)
      18 1/8 x 24 1/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 3032-1121 Vermont House (Box 39)
      19 1/8 x 25 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 3033-1121 Vermont House from Hill (Box 39)
      12 1/8 x 19 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 3034-1121 The Vermont House (Box 39)
      19 1/8 x 25 7/8 Oil paint and charcoal on paper
    - 3035-1121 Chinese Head (Box 39)
      Item 3029-1121 is also a print and 3049 is the corresponding plate. 25 1/2 x 15 1/4 Lithograph, Ink on paper
    - 3036-1121 A House in Vermont (Box 39)
      19 1/8 x 25 1/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 3037-1121 A House in Vermont (Box 39)
      25 1/4 x 19 1/8 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 3038-1121 Vermont House (Box 39)
      15 1/4 x 19 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 3039-1121 Lillian - Yaddo (Box 39)
      24 1/2 x 17 Monotype, Ink on paper
    - 3040-1121 Seated Figure - Yaddo (Box 39)
    - 3041-1121 Landscape - Yaddo (Box 39)
    - 3042-1121 [Landscape] - Yaddo (Box 39)
      17 x 24 1/2 Monotype, Ink on paper
    - 3043-1121 [Landscape] [With Building] - Yaddo (Box 39)
    - 3044-1121 Memory of Romanesque - Yaddo (Box 39)
    - 3045-1121 Hyde Solomon - Yaddo (Box 39)
      24 1/4 x 17 Monotype, Ink on paper
    - 3046-1121 Hyde Solomon - Yaddo (Box 39)
    - 3047-1121 Clowns - Yaddo (Box 39)
      20 x 24 1/4 Monotype, Ink on paper
    - 3048-1121 Memory of a Romanesque - Yaddo (Box 39)
      Recto and verso. 24 1/4 x 20 Monotype, Ink on paper
    - 3049-1121 Chinese Head (Box 39)
      Accompanied by two prints. 25 1/2 x 15 1/4 Lithographic plate, Ink on paper
      Items 3029-1121 and 3035 are also prints. 25 1/2 x 15 1/4 Lithographic plate, Ink on paper
    - 3050-1121 Abstraction with Black Disc (Box 40)
    - 3051-1121 Interior, Studio - Vermont (Box 40)
    - 3052-1121 Children Playing in Vermont (Box 40)
      13 1/2 x 13 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 3053-1121 After a Painting Unfinished on Kurt Seligman's Easel (Box 40)
      Marked CU15. 13 x 12 1/4 Etching, Ink on paper
    - 3054-1121 Lillian (Box 40)
      19 x 12 1/2 Oil paint on paper
    - 3055-1121 Lillian Nursing Ernst (Box 40)
    - 3056-1121 Lillian (Box 40)
      12 1/2 x 10 Crayon on paper
    - 3057-1121 Wagon Ride - Vermont (Box 40)
      19 x 9 1/2 Charcoal on paper
    - 3058-1121 Miriam (Box 40)
    - 3059-1121 [Lillian and Miriam and Teddy and Howard] (Box 40)
    - 3060-1121 Vermont - Sketch (Box 40)
      12 x 19 Oil paint and graphite pencil on paper
    - 3061-1121 Lillian Sleeping (Box 40)
      20 x 12 1/4 Graphite pencil on paper
    - 3062-1121 Lillian Sleeping (Box 40)
    - 3063-1121 Lillian Sleeping (Box 40)
      20 1/8 x 11 3/4 Pastels on paper
    - 3064-1121 Lillian Sleeping (Box 40)
      20 1/8 x 12 3/8 Pastels on paper
    - 3065-1121 Lillian Sleeping (Box 40)
      19 7/8 x 12 1/4 Pastels on paper
    - 3066-1121 Lillian (Box 40)
      20 x 14 Crayon on paper
    - 3067-1121 Vermont Landscape (Box 40)
    - 3068-1121 Hudson River Seen From Mountain Side (Box 40)
      12 3/4 x 10 1/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 3069-1121 Untitled (Box 40)
      Attribution to Meyer Schapiro uncertain. 6 3/4 x 7 7/8 Etching, Ink on paper
      Accompanied by one additional print. 6 3/4 x 7 7/8 Etching, Ink on paper
    - 3070-1121 By Katherine Milgram-Shaw (Box 40)
      Accompanied by additional sheet. 11 3/8 x 8 3/4 Ink on paper
    - 3071-1121 Untitled (Box 40)
      Inscribed: by Ernest Schapiro. 19 x 12 3/4 Crayon on paper
    - 3072-1121 Untitled (Box 40)
      Inscribed on recto: Miriam Schapiro, 6th Class. 10 3/8 x 13 Paint on paper
    - 3073-1121 Twilight Scene (Box 40)
      Marked C39. 11 x 8 1/2 Oil paint and pastels on paper
    - 3074-1121 Vertical Colour Bands (Box 40)
      Marked C45. 12 3/4 x 17 3/4 Oil paint on paper
    - 3075-1121 Landscape - Black Zig-Zags and Color Patches #2 (Box 40)
    - 3076-1121 Dora Milgram - Rawsonville (Box 40)
      19 x 12 1/2 Oil paint and charcoal on paper
    - 3077-1121 Hyde Solomon at Yaddo (Box 40)
      20 1/2 x 14 1/4 Oil paint and charcoal on paper
    - 3078-1121 Lillian and Miriam (Box 40)
      19 x 12 1/2 Oil paint and graphite pencil on paper
    - 3079-1121 Miriam on Rocking Chair (Box 40)
      14 5/8 x 19 Oil paint and graphite pencil on paper
    - 3080-1121 Front Door - Vermont (Box 40)
      12 x 21 Oil paint on paper
    - 3081-1121 Hill Side (Box 40)
    - 3082-1121 Abstraction (Box 40)
    - 3083-1121 Rectangles (Box 40)
      12 x 17 1/4 Gouache on paper
    - 3084-1121 Hill House - Rawsonville (Box 40)
    - 3085-1121 Vague Forms (Box 40)
    - 3086-1121 Miriam on Rug in Vermont Living Room (Box 41)
      14 3/4 x 19 1/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 3087-1121 [Abstracted] (Box 41)
    - 3088-1121 Vermont (Box 41)
      14 1/8 x 11 Oil paint on paper
    - 3089-1121 Belmont, Vermont (Box 41)
      9 1/4 x 13 1/8 Gouache on paper
    - 3090-1121 Untitled (Box 41)
      Marked CU77 and "from XLVII." 8 1/4 x 9 1/4 Gouache on paper
    - 3091-1121 [Howard Shaw] (Box 41)
      19 x 12 1/2 Crayon on paper
    - 3092-1121 Untitled (Box 41)
    - 3093-1121 Untitled (Box 41)
    - 3094-1121 Untitled (Box 41)
    - 3095-1121 Abstraction - Four-Sided Forms (Box 41)
    - 3096-1121 Rawsonville Landscapes (Box 41)
      10 x 9 Oil paint on paper
    - 3097-1121 Abstraction with Reserved Whites (Box 41)
      7 1/2 x 8 3/8 Tempera on paper
    - 3098-1121 Abstraction with Blues (Box 41)
    - 3099-1121 Abstraction - Calligraphic Shapes (Box 41)
    - 3100-1121 Vermont (Box 41)
      12 x 15 Oil paint on paper
    - 3101-1121 Figure (Box 41)
      12 x 14 Crayon on paper
    - 3102-1121 Meyer, Lillian, Miriam and Dada (Box 41)
      19 1/8 x 14 5/8 Oil paint on paper
    - 3103-1121 Untitled (Box 42)
      19 3/4 x 24 1/2 Raised relief, Plaster on fiberboard
  - Subseries VIII.4: Sculptures and printing plates, circa 1930s-1980s
    - 4 wood sculptures 2 wood bases. (Box 42)
    - 1 wood sculpture. (Box 43)
    - 1 cut-copper sculpture with wood base (damaged) 2 clay sculptures (both damaged) 1 plaster sculpture. (Box 44)
    - 3104-1121 Untitled (Box 45)
      2 1/2 x 3 1/8 Copper printing plate
    - 3105-1121 Untitled (Box 46)
      3 3/8 x 3 Copper printing plate
    - 3106-1121 [Andre Racz] (Box 46)
      See item 2356-1121. 7 x 5 Printing plate
    - 3107-1121 Lillian (Box 46)
      See item 2353-1121. 5 x 4 Copper printing plate
    - 3108-1121 New York View (Box 46)
      See item 2348-1121. 5 x 4 Printing plate
    - 3109-1121 Sarah Levine (Box 46)
      See item 2463-1121. 6 x 4 Printing plate
    - 3110-1121 Flowers and Window - My First Etching (Box 46)
      See item 2475-1121. 5 x 4 Printing plate
    - 3111-1121 My Second Etching (Box 46)
      See item 2389-1121. 5 x 4 Printing plate
    - 3171-1121 Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Science building, Stanford (Box 46)
      5 x 4 Printing plate
    - 1 cut-copper sculpture on wood base. (Box 47)
    - 1 cut-copper sculpture on wood base (damaged) 2 aluminum-cut sculptures on wood bases 1 unfinished wood carving and one wood block with sketch affixed. (Box 48)
    - 1 wood sculpture. (Box 49)
  - Subseries VIII.5: Linoleum printing blocks, circa 1930s-1960s
    Box 50 contains the original Linoleum printing blocks for the prints found in box 24 and box 25.
    - 3112-1121 Eve (Box 50)
      5 1/2 x 3 1/8 Linoleum printing block
    - 3113-1121 Wrestlers (Box 50)
      7 7/8 x 7 1/4 Linoleum printing block
    - 3114-1121 Vermont (Box 50)
      6 x 5 Linoleum printing block
    - 3115-1121 Deposition (Box 50)
      3 1/2 x 4 1/8 Linoleum printing block
    - 3116-1121 Memory of Camping with Whittaker Chambers Near His House (Box 50)
      8 x 7 1/2 Linoleum printing block
    - 3117-1121 Sledding (Box 50)
      5 3/4 x 5 3/7 Linoleum printing block
    - 3118-1121 Crucifixion (Box 50)
      4 1/4 x 7 5/8 Linoleum printing block
    - 3119-112 After Holbein's Portrait, 1 (Box 50)
      5 7/8 x 4 7/8 Linoleum printing block
    - 3120-1121 Imaginary Murder (Box 50)
      4 1/2 x 5 1/2 Linoleum printing block
    - 3121-1121 New Year Card (Box 50)
      13 x 11 Linoleum printing block
    - 3122-1121 Phoenix (Box 50)
      4 1/8 x 6 Linoleum printing block
    - 3123-1121 Female (Box 50)
      7 1/4 x 5 3/4 Linoleum printing block
    - 3124-1121 The Ferry (Box 50)
      6 1/2 x 4 1/8 Linoleum printing block
    - 3125-1121 Untitled (Box 50)
      See item 2337-1121. 5 1/2 x 5 3/4 Linoleum printing block
    - 3126-1121 Flagellation (Box 50)
      7 3/4 x 5 1/2 Linoleum printing block
    - 3127-1121 "Janie's" New Year Card (Box 50)
    - 3128-1121 Untitled (Box 50)
      7 1/4 x 6 3/8 Linoleum printing block
    - 3129-1121 Untitled (Box 50)
      4 x 6 Linoleum printing block
    - 3130-1121 Untitled (Box 50)
      12 1/2 x 13 1/4 Linoleum printing block
    - 3131-1121 Untitled (Box 50)
      7 1/2 x 7 Linoleum printing block
  - Subseries VIII.6: Sketchbooks, 1960s
    - 3132-1121 Tokyo 1966 - "P" (Box 52)
      Marked CU37. 4 5/8 x 6 3/4
    - 3133-1121 Sketchbook "HH" (Box 52)
      8 1/4 x 5 5/8
    - 3134-1121 Sketchbook "EE" (Box 52)
      Contains drawings of Sophie(1968). 8 1/4 x 5 1/2
    - 3135-1121 Sketchbook "G" (Box 52)
      Contains mainly landscapes and self-portraits. 8 1/4 x 5 1/2
    - 3136-1121 Mustair 1961 - Sketchbook "F" (Box 52)
      8 x 5 1/4
    - 3137-1121 Etretat, August 1939; Le Havre; Boat, September 1939 - Sketchbook "H" (Box 52)
      7 3/4 x 5 3/4
    - 3138-1121 Sketchbook "CC" (Box 52)
      Marked CU28. 7 3/4 x 5 3/4
    - 3139-1121 California and Canada - Sketchbook "L" (Box 52)
      8 1/4 x 5 3/4
    - 3140-1121 Sketchbook "FF" (Box 52)
      8 1/4 x 5 1/2
    - 3141-1121 West Coast - Sketchbook "K" (Box 52)
    - 3142-1121 Sketchbook "MM" (Box 52)
      Contains sketches of Lillian. 8 1/4 x 5 3/4
    - 3143-1121 Utah and Nevada - Sketchbook "N" (Box 52)
      6 3/4 x 4 1/2
    - 3144-1121 Later 1950s, 1960-1962 Vermont - Sketchbook "E" (Box 52)
      6 3/4 x 5 1/2
    - 3145-1121 Vermont 1950s-1970s - Sketchbook "PP" (Box 52)
    - 3146-1121 Vermont 1961-1965 and 1971 - Sketchbook "V" (Box 52)
      Marked CU40. 7 1/8 x 5 1/4
    - 3147-1121 Yaddo and Saratoga, Also Vermont - Sketchbook "U" (Box 52)
      Marked CU39. 7 1/4 x 5 1/4
    - 3148-1121 New York - Sketchbook "T" (Box 52)
      Marked CU34. 6 3/4 x 4 1/8
    - 3149-1121 Vermont 1950s - Sketchbook "B" (Box 52)
    - 3150-1121 Sketchbook "BB" (Box 52)
      Marked CU30. 6 3/4 x 4 1/2
    - 3151-1121 Sketchbook (Box 52)
      Marked CU29. 8 1/2 x 6 3/4
    - 3152-1121 Columbia College 1923-1924 (Box 52)
      Contains analyses of paintings and sketches of Columbia campus. 8 1/2 x 11
    - 3153-1121 Trip to California 1962- Sketchbook "C" (Box 52)
      10 x 8
    - 3154-1121 At Joe's, Marlboro - Sketchbook "I" (Box 52)
      6 1/2 x 10
    - 3155-1121 Vermont (Box 52)
      8 1/4 x 6 `1/2
    - 3156-1121 [New York] - Sketchbook "QQ" (Box 52)
      6 x 9
    - 3157-1121 Untitled (Box 52)
      9 3/4 x 6 1/4
    - 3158-1121 Untitled (Box 52)
      5 1/8 x 3 5/8
    - 3159-1121 Untitled (Box 52)
      6 x 4
    - 3160-1121 Untitled" (Box 52)
      Marked CU45. 7 1/2 x 4 7/8
    - 3161-1121 Mary Sklar's Sketchbook (Box 53)
    - 3162-1121 Sketchbook "AA" (Box 53)
      8 3/4 x 12
    - 3163-1121 Sketchbook "GG" (Box 53)
      9 3/4 x 8 1/2
    - 3164-1121 Starting 1965 - Sketchbook "JJ" (Box 53)
      12 1/4 x 9
    - 3165-1121 New York 1960s - Sketchbook "W" (Box 53)
    - 3166-1121 Sketchbook "II" (Box 53)
      13 x 9 3/4
    - 3167-1121 California - Sketchbook "Y" (Box 54)
      Marked CU35. 11 x 14
    - 3168-1121 Paris 1931 - Sketchbook "NN" (Box 54)
      Marked XXIV. 13 x 16
    - 3169-1121 Sarasota 1969- Sketchbook "OO" (Box 54)
      14 x 17
    - 3170-1121 Sketchbook (Box 54)